Kimsan Mak

Geoscientist / Data Analyst (MBA) Bonn, Germany +49 15906493534 <u>kimsan.mak@gmx.de</u> GitHub: Portfolio

PERSONAL PROFILE

A certified data analyst with experience in geosciences who undertakes data mining to uncover patterns, trends, and relationships between features. My experience in managing mining projects, and researching mineral deposits and groundwater modelling has strengthened my project management and data analysis skills. I want to use my experience and skill sets to assist you in exploring the mysterious world of data, making sense of the numbers, and utilizing the findings to discover your "gold mine"

SKILL SETS

Data Analytics

Python: Group & Aggregate /
Regression Supervised ML / Clustering
Unsupervised ML / Time Series Data
SQL: Join / Query / Subquery / CTE
Tableau: Statistical Analysis / Spatial
Analysis / Dashboard / Storyboard
Excel: Pivot Table / Statistics / VBA

Geological & Groundwater

Geological & Mineral Resource Modelling / Feasibility Study / Aquifer Characterization / Flow & Transport Modelling / Dewatering Management

Soft Skills

Teamwork / Communication / Problem-solving/ Adaptability / Political and Cultural Awareness / Resilient

Tools

Micromine© / Geosoft Target / ArcGIS / MODFLOW / PMWIN / Adobe Photoshop

Languages

Mandarin (native) / English (fluent) / Germany (proficient) / Malay (fluent)

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry, Data Analytics (2024) University of Maastricht, MBA (2017) University of Tübingen, M.Sc. Applied

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Consulting Geologist, Self-employed / Germany (07.2020 - present)

- conduct research, data assessment, onsite due diligence, and assistance in acquisition of mineral exploration projects
- hydrogeological survey, groundwater modelling, and building site dewatering management for companies in Germany

Challenges: steep learning curve in setting up as freelancer in Germany, and overcoming the language and cultural barrier.

Deputy COO, Soremi SA / Republic of Congo (06.2019-05.2020)

- directed improvement on data collection, data quality management system, and data analysis of a copper-cathode producing mine which generates an annual revenue of + \$100 million
- fast-tracked near-mine brownfield drilling and greenfield exploration over an area of 5,500 km²

Achievement: built trust and sought common goals to enhance cooperation between the partners.

Exploration Manager, Azumah Resources Ltd. / Ghana (02.2012-07.2014)

- managed the whole gold project and feasibility study with the assistance of 16 team members, consultants and contractors
- improved data-driven operation, and systematically screened 3,400 km² license area with various work programmes
- managed stakeholders in facilitating mitigation of socialenvironmental fallout from artisanal gold mining, and disseminating project information to the community

Achievement: expanded gold resources from 1,67 to 2,20 Moz. within 3 months and successfully completed the feasibility study in 14 months.

Technical Manager, Signet Mining Ltd. / South Africa (04.2008-04.2010)

- provided technical support, data management and analysis for uranium exploration teams in Chad and Niger
- conducted geostatistical analysis, resource modelling, and assisted in technical-financial evaluations of mining projects in Africa

Challenges: developed political and cultural awareness, integrity and strong work ethics to work in a very challenging environment.

Senior Consultant, ERM Shanghai / China (08.2005-07.2007)

- led a team of consultants in executing geotechnical engineering surveys, soil and groundwater environmental risk assessments, and environmental compliance audits for international companies
- involved in various sector-related environmental issues, e.g., construction, chemicals production, petrochemical refinery, machinery and electronics manufacturing.

Achievement: adapted quickly to new working environment and industrial domains, and switched from project owner to service provider mentality

Geologist, BHP Billiton / Asia (05.1994-07.1999)

- executed data generation, data analysis, and set up data management system for various projects
- involved in various regional data assessment, i.e., geology, geochemistry and geophysics, regional exploration targets generation for gold, copper, nickel, lead and zinc exploration projects